My name is Ed Warren.
here with my wife. Lorraine.
and Victoria Grainger.
It's April 20th. 1964.
Victoria... when did you first notice
these supernatural occurrences?
I'm sorry.
I don't know how to do this.
Why don't you just
take us back to the beginning?
My father thought
something was following him.
Something he couldn't see.
He'd lock the doors at night.
and the next morning. they...
...they'd be open.
Then he started hearing...
...voices.
I didn't believe him.
I thought he was getting old. you know?
But then I came in one day. and...
I found him.
Dad!
It was so quiet here after he was gone.
But then something changed.
I could feel it.
This really strong feeling. like...
...like I'm being watched.
There's something in there.
And when I'm here alone...
and it's very quiet...
...it calls to me.
Hon...
I don't know.
I don't have a good feeling about this.
Ed. I can do this.
Lorraine...
My name is Lorraine Warren.
I'm here to help.
I can...  feel your spirit.
Your fear.
There's something else.
What are you?
Ed!
- Lorraine! Lorraine?
-  Ed!
Lorraine. what happened?
The baby!
The hospital's ten minutes away!
What was that back there?
I don't know!
There was something...
in the room.
In the mirror.
I don't know.
-  When's the baby due?
- May. She's early!
Okay. notify Labor and Delivery.
We're coming in
with a possible abruption!
- She's abrupting.
-  It's gonna be okay.
Ed! Something's wrong. I can feel it!
- It's okay. It's gonna be all right.
- Sir? Sir. you have to stay out here.
- No. Lorraine! Lorraine!
- Sir! Sir!
Lorraine! Lorraine!
We need to get the baby out.
You've gotta push.
She's losing blood.
- We got blood on the way?
-  Yes.
Where's Ed?
How's the baby?
-  What's her vitals?
- Where's Ed?
Pulse. 130.
Pressure. 80 over 40.
Damn it!
Get me a flashlight.
Something's here!
Power's out! Lorraine!
- No. no! Lorraine?
- Ed!
Please-- No. please.
I need to talk to my wife.
Don't get in the way.
Ed...
Don't let it hurt the baby.
Don't let what hurt the baby?
Please.
All right. the head's right here.
You need to push. Mrs. Warren.
Stop pushing! The head's out.
The cord's around the neck.
I need two clamps and scissors.
What?  What'd he say?
What's wrong?
One more push.
We gotta get this baby out.
Okay. It's okay.
It's coming. It's coming.
I need that light.
She's still bleeding.
Something's wrong.
What's wrong with her?
-  Something's wrong!
- Do you need help?
Please.
Doctor. what's wrong?
Doctor. what's happening? What's going on?
Give me my baby.
Give me my baby!
I'm so sorry.
Oh.
God.
Oh. please. Heavenly Father.
Please. bring her back.
Oh. God.
Heavenly father. please...
Please. bring her back.
Oh. God. please.
Please. Please...
Oh. my God! Oh!
Oh... oh!
Oh.
What's her name?
Her name is Judy.
Judy Warren.
Come on. Come here.
Come on. baby.
So good.
So good!
Judy!
What? Honey.
Honey.
I keep seeing horrible things!
And they won't go away!
Oh. hon!
All right. all right.
Just shut it out.
just like I taught you. okay?
Just like I taught you.
♪ Lucy Locket lost her pocket ♪
- ♪ Kitty Fisher found it ♪
- ♪ Not a penny was there in it ♪
- ♪ Only ribbon 'round it ♪
- ♪ You're not there ♪
Those things. what if I can't
make them go away?
You can.
Mm-hmm.
You can. It's your choice.
It's your choice. hon.
Come here.
I love you.
I love you. too.
My baby...
Come on. boy.
Good boy.
Mom told me to get some decorations
from the attic.
Well. quickly. Come on. everybody!
They're not holding Mass just for us!
Come on. Dad. Turn the TV off.
Thank you. honey.
- Damn it!
-  Language. Heather!
Carin. get down from there.
- Don't forget the camera.
- It's charged?
Thank you.
Mom!
-  Heather. what?
- It's a disaster!
Dawn was hogging the bathroom all morning.
- I was not!
- Oh. she was!
There was no hot water left.
And when I tried to dry my hair.
the outlet blew out!
Mom. just give me a minute.
Honey. there's still time
to fix your hair. right?
And you look so beautiful in this dress!
Yeah. let's not lie to her. Grandma.
I'm gonna kill you!
You can't kill her on your confirmation.
Milo Evans Roberts.
be sealed with the gift
of the Holy Spirit.
-  Amen.
- I don't know.
- Honey. you're in the shot.
- Here she comes.
Get out of the way.
Sorry. thank you.
Oh. doesn't she look beautiful?
...Holy Spirit.
Peace be with you.
Heather Elizabeth Smurl.
be sealed with the gift
of the Holy Spirit.
Amen.
Peace be with you.
There she is.
She's confirmed.
You did it. honey.
- Hey. girls! Who wants dinner?
- We do!
- Come on! Get inside. then!
- I'm super hungry!
Hurry. hurry! Chop. chop. chop!
It's getting cold!
...to call.
Yes. it was a beautiful ceremony.
- John. stop!
- Oh. honey!
You know how much I love your dips!
- Ah! I love it!
- Ugh...
- Hold on...
- Where should I put the salad?
Mm-hmm.
Grandma?
Where do you want the salad?
You two think you're so funny!
Hey. what's all this noise?
- Sorry. that was the girls.
- Hey. no running in the house. girls.
Okay. Round up. round up.
What do we have here?
It's taller than I am!
Oh. my gosh!
I didn't get anything for my confirmation.
- Dawn...
- I thought we got you that nice brooch?
-  Yeah.
- Oh. yeah...
Yeah. there was that.
-  Go on. open it.
- Okay.
It's a mirror.
It's got a crack.
-  Oh. Heather...
-  Oh. sweetie.
Grandpa can fix the glass.
We found it at the swap meet.
over in Bucks County.
-  Simon. hush!
- You did?
Hey...
I love it.
Thanks. Grandpa.
- Oh. honey. you're welcome.
- Thanks. Gran.
Oh. sweetheart!
- Mom. I hope it wasn't too much.
- Oh. don't worry.
The man couldn't get it back in his truck.
so he gave us a little deal.
I think it was just waiting for us.
We know the bathroom gets crowded.
You can put it in your room.
and you don't have to share with anyone.
- That's a good idea.
-  That is not going
- in our bedroom.
-  Well. I...
-  Are you serious?
- ...think it's lovely...
...and very thoughtful.
No more queues.
Doesn't the one up at the top
look just like you when you were a baby?
Oh. yeah. definitely.
I can see that.
Ow!
-  Heather!
- My foot slipped.
It did not. I saw that.
- Okay. seriously. though.
- Dawn's foot got in the way.
Not now. Right...
That resemblance is crazy.
- You've got the bangs and everything.
- Who wants cake?
I do! I do! I do!
Okay!
-  Come on. There we go!
-  There we go!
It looks so good.
Confirmation cake!
-  Congratulations. sweetheart.
- Thank you.
I definitely didn't get a cake.
Don't forget to make a wish.
Simon. hush!
Simon wants some cake. too.
Here we go!
Ready?
Hey. what? She blew out my candles.
- Who?
- Dawn!
- No. I didn't!
- You did!
-  No. I didn't!
-  Get some light on.
-  It's all right.
- I actually didn't blow them out.
It's okay. guys.
Come on. let's have a bit of peace.
She did.
Oh. my God!
Heather! Oh. my God!
Heather! Are you okay?
It's okay. What's wrong?
Oh. my God.
Dad? That is a lot of blood.
Did it hit you?
Oh. my God. are you hurt?
Hey. it's okay. it's okay.
Just squeeze my hand.
- It's okay. It's okay.
- I'll go and get the first aid kit!
Subtitle
www.movieddl.me
The young occupants of the apartment
thought they were speaking to the spirit
of a little girl named Annabelle Mullins.
But in reality. they were communing
with an inhuman spirit.
A demon.
It played on their sympathies.
It played on their compassion.
It then asked for permission
to enter the doll as its vessel.
a conduit into our world.
We've encountered hundreds
of items like Annabelle.
Cursed objects. totems...
...and over the years. we've found that
the best solution was to collect them.
It's like taking guns off the streets.
Hang on. sorry.
You know what?
Will one of you hit the lights?
All right.
Okay. Uh. any questions?
Yes?
So. you guys were
kind of like The Ghostbusters?
Uh. no. We didn't... bust ghosts.
But we did see the movie.
Wait! So. you never got slimed?
Please...
Any serious questions?
Yes?
Why did you stop?
We haven't stopped.
We're travelling. we're doing lectures.
We may even write a book.
But you're not taking cases anymore.
Well. we've decided to. um.
to focus on other parts of our life.
Mm.
Let's get out of here.
"Who ya gonna call?"
Well... thank you.
Our entire life's work...
It's like some sort of
Saturday Night Live skit.
Wha-- It's not funny!
Dad. it wasn't that bad!
Hon. I think you're not seeing
the forest for the trees.
Or the ghosts for the graveyard.
Oh. great.
People weren't even listening. though.
They're not even engaged anymore.
It's like they're just all
waiting for a punchline.
They're just having fun.
I guess.
When they asked why you guys quit.
why didn't you just say.
'cause of your heart?
Because that's what an old man would say.
Besides. it-it's more a hiatus
than retirement.
It's... It's just until
the doc clears me again.
Right. hon?
Well. in the meantime.
we have your birthday coming up.
- Mm-hmm.
- And I was thinking
of bringing Tony to the party.
Who's Tony?
Dad! We've been dating for six months.
Oh. that Tony.
You're not funny.
Of course. sweetheart. We love him.
- We do?
- Ed.
- We do.
-  You guys ready?
- Yeah.
- Yes.
I'll have the linguine with clams. please.
-  Yeah. great choice.
- Okay.
Who's next?
Uh. yeah. I can do it.
Um...
Boy. you got
a lot of good stuff here. Um...
I'm on
a bit of a heart healthy diet...
♪ ...found it
Not a penny was there in it ♪
♪ Only ribbon 'round it ♪
♪ Not a penny was there in it
Only ribbon 'round it ♪
♪ Lucy Locket lost her pocket
Kitty Fisher found it ♪
♪ Not a penny was there in it
Only ribbon 'round it ♪
♪ Lucy Locket lost her pocket
Kitty Fisher found it ♪
♪ Not a penny was there in it
Only ribbon 'round it ♪
♪ You're not there ♪
♪ Lucy Locket lost her pocket-- ♪
Grilled steak slices...
...over mixed greens. Let's do that.
Can I get that but with chicken?
Sure.
Dressing on the side?
Lorraine?
Ma'am? You okay?
Yes.
Yes. I'm-- I'm--
I'm fine. I thought--
I thought I saw something.
I'm fine.
Did you make up your mind?
- Sorry. What?
- The lasagna.
She loves the lasagna.
Right. sweetheart?
Yeah. great choice. Thank you.
Thank you.
Nice. It's coming right up.
You two all right?
Yeah.
Wish I could have lasagna.
Mommy. Mommy!
What are you doing in here?
Mom--
Janet...
No.
No. that's what Margie was saying.
Wait! We're gonna be late
for Mister Pinky Pop's birthday party.
I knew that they were having problems.
I just didn't know it was that bad.
Hurry up. Shannon!
He's gonna be
- really mad if you're late.
- What a shame.
Come on!
No.
Girls. stop it!
I don't think that that's true.
Alice wouldn't want that.
Known her since we were in high school.
No.
She didn't say that. no.
Girls!
Girls. you come outta there. right now!
Janet. are you there?
Did I lose ya?
Janet?
Hello?
Here you go.
You want some soup?
'Kay. Susie. I'm gonna
make you some soup.
and I'll be right back with you.
"Okay!"
You can.
So. here. it says "welcome." Oh.
Here's corn.
Can you make that carrot soup
that we like?
Of course!
- And when do you want this?
- Okay. perfect!
Okay. made your soup for you. Susie.
Where's Susie?
Mommy. Mommy!
How did you get in here. Susie?
Mommy! Mommy!
Mommy!
Hey. hey. hey...
- Come here. come here!
-  She stole my doll.
- You have a good day?
-  She stole Susie!
You been a good boy?
Good boy.
- Hey. Dad. What are you watching?
- Hi. son.
- It's not very good.
- Mommy! Mom. she stole my doll!
- Hello. everyone!
- She stole Susie!
Hi. sweetie.
- Okay.
- Could you get the cutlery out over there?
Daddy. no one believes me!
-  What?
-  Sorry. Mom.
-  She's speaking nonsense!
- Believes you what?
I'm not!
I'll believe you.
You just tell me what this is about.
- I was playing in Dawn's room...
- Thank you for the floodlights.
- ...with Susie. and then--
- Shannon! She thinks she saw...
- No one believes me. Granddad!
- ...an old woman in Dawn's room.
-  Yeah. I believe you!
- Okay.
- That's everything. Sit down.
- An old lady took Susie.
- I was at the store.
- Simon believes you.
Simon believes...
- Grandma. stop scaring Carin.
- Come on. sit down.
All right. everyone.
I am hungry. Let's eat.
- Why does no one believe me?
- I'll believe you.
You can tell me all about it after dinner.
Please sit down. sweetheart.
-  All right.
-  Squeeze in. Carin.
- Come on. sit down.
- Maybe it was Grandma.
All right!
Okay.
For what we're about to receive.
may the Lord make us truly thankful.
- Amen.
All right. let's eat.
- This looks great!
- I want some meatballs!
Meatballs are my favorite.
- It's so weird.
- I know you are.
Wait. what's weird?
The mirror.
Ugh. I know.
It's like those creepy-looking
babies are always watching me.
Well. babies are perverts.
Babies are gross.
Seriously.
"The one in the middle
looks just like you. Heather."
That was so funny. but that's a lie.
You were a much uglier baby.
Jeez. thanks.
You know. you should've seen the cards
Mom and Dad got in the hospital.
"Janet. we're so sorry
your daughter came out
looking like that guy Sloth from Goonies."
You're an asshole!
You know.
it's trash day tomorrow.
Ow.
Let's take it 'round the bend.
Oh. my God. that was so heavy!
What if Grandma asks about it?
It was the twins. They did it.
They broke it. We just took it outside.
Good idea.
I know. I'm a genius.
Morning. everyone. Carin!
Get down from there. What's she doing?
- Stay. Simon. stay. Simon. go!
- Carin. come on down.
Carin. come on now. Sit down.
- Making me some sandwiches?
- Honey.
I am making the girls some sandwiches.
- What about my lunch?
- I've got your lunch.
"Win a family vacation to Florida."
- Oh. my gosh!
- How cool would that be?
Pretty cool.
- You really stink. Simon.
- He's farting all the time. now.
That's the bacon.
-  I don't really...
- No!
Don't slap me with cheese.
You know what happened.
the last time you slapped me with cheese?
- What?
- I was down on my knees. Mm-mm!
I got it.
- Get the other end of this?
- Yep.
- You ready?
- It'll fit.
Yeah. I don't own a piggy bank.
I don't have two dollars.
I don't have one.
It's just a prank.
Yeah. maybe we'll have two dollars.
Four dollars!
Yeah. that would be good.
Well. you have a birthday coming up soon.
Are you okay?
- Dawn?
- Sweetheart?
Are you okay?
-  Honey?
-  Come on.
- You okay. Dawn?
-  Dawn?
Mm! Mm...
Dawn. can you breathe okay?
- Are you choking?
- Are you choking. sweetheart?
Oh. God! Oh. Dawn!
Honey. Oh. my gosh.
Oh. my God. no!
-  You'll be okay.
-  Oh. my God.
- Oh. Dawn!
- Oh. Dawny!
Oh. my God!
Dawn!
It's okay.
What is that?
Is that glass? Did you swallow glass?
We've gotta get to the hospital.
- Yes.
- Go!
Get her to the hospital!
God. Jack!
It's gonna be all right.
Yeah. yeah. it will.
- It's gonna be okay.
-  Sweetheart.
come and sit down. sweetie.
Heather. sweetheart.
Come on.
That bad?
Higher than I'd like.
You ever think about adding fish
to your diet?
I'm not really a fish guy. doc.
What about egg whites?
Egg what?
Ed...
I've known you a long time. Cut the crap.
Excuse me?
You can't have another heart attack.
Yeah.
♪ Love has me by the hand
And I will follow ♪
Hannah... Out. out!
Out. out. out!
- Hi. it's good to see you.
- How are you?
Lorraine. good to see you.
Look. help yourself to the hors d'oeuvres.
I'll be right out.
Okay.
Okay...
- What was that for?
- Just...
...to thank you for this wonderful party.
All my favorite people are right...
...here.
Happy birthday. Ed.
Uh-- She's here.
Okay.
Tony. you're acting so nervous!
What? I'm not nervous.
I just really
want them to approve.
Of what?
I don't know. Uh. you know. me. us.
You've got nothing
to worry about.
My mom loves you.
What about your dad?
Your dad doesn't like me?
-  Stop!
- Are you serious?
- You're telling me this now?
- I didn't say that! Come on.
What's with the tie? It's not a funeral.
So now I'm not even dressed right.
Oh. my God.
All right. Where are we?
Is she here?
- Oh! Aw...
- Happy birthday. Dad!
- Thank you. sweetie.
- Hey. Mom.
- Tommy?
- Dad. it's Tony!
- That's what I said.
- Happy birthday. Mr. Warren.
- Thank you.
- Tony. you look so handsome.
Oh. please. come on in.
Hey. what's with the tie?
It's not a funeral.
What?
Judy?
- Father Gordon. Hi!
- Oh. my goodness!
It's so good to see you.
- Honey?
-  You have gotten taller.
He always says that.
Um. this is my boyfriend. Tony.
Tony. this is my Father Gordon.
He used to work with my mom and dad.
- It's nice to meet you. Tony.
- And you.
So. what do you do?
Oh. uh... I am between jobs. actually.
Oh. okay.
Tony was a police officer.
Call it early retirement.
You're quite young for retirement. son.
Huh?
Yeah. it's. uh...
It's a long story.
All right.
Be careful not to touch anything.
So. everything you see in there
is either haunted. cursed.
or has been used in some sort of. uh...
ritualistic practice.
What's in there?
All the skeletons.
What? Wait. really?
Baby. hand me my beer.
Thank you.
Maybe one more?
Hey.
Smells good.
S-Sorry. uh. I'm Tony.
I know who you are.
You're Judy's boyfriend.
Yeah.
Brad Hamilton.
I used to work with the Warrens.
Oh...
What. like.
on their investigations?
Here and there. yeah.
Sometimes consulting.
sometimes... security.
Hey. did you ever see an exorcism?
Did I ever see an exorcism?
Front row. baby. Right there.
That's a battle scar.
She nearly bit off my entire cheek.
She did that?
Yeah.
And they say Rhode Island's boring.
I don't know.
Why don't you get a bun. Tony?
♪ Lucy Locket lost her pocket ♪
♪ Kitty Fisher found it ♪
♪ Not a penny was there in it ♪
♪ Only ribbon 'round it ♪
♪ You're... ♪
♪ Not... ♪
♪ ...There ♪
Sorry.
You okay?
Yeah.
Did you... see something?
It's nothing.
Hey.
I'm sorry. This is weird.
I'm-- I'm being weird.
I...
I love weird.
I mean. I love you.
I love... you.
Hey. what were you saying. when I came in?
Um...
Just this trick my mom taught me.
What kinda trick?
Um...
It's how I learned to deal with my...
...um. senses.
How to shut them out.
Okay. Um. how did it go again?
No. seriously. Teach me.
It's embarrassing.
I wanna know.
You can't be embarrassed in front of me.
Please?
Okay. but you can't laugh.
I will not laugh.
♪ Lucy Locket... ♪
♪ ...Lost her pocket ♪
Poor Lucy.
No... Actually. wait.
I came in. You had your eyes closed.
That's gotta be part of it. no?
Fine.
♪ Lucy Locket... ♪
♪ ...Lost her pocket ♪
♪ Kitty Fisher found it ♪
- ♪ Kitty Fisher... ♪
- ♪ Not a... ♪
Hey.
What?
Cheating.
Sorry.
Oh! I'm so sorry.
- Mom!
- Mrs. Warren!
Um...
Tony. Ed was looking for you.
He's taking some of the guys
to the garage.
Oh. so... Like. me?
Yes. if-- if you want.
Uh. yeah. Sure.
I should probably...
Judy. wait.
What's going on?
Nothing. I'm fine.
The other night. at the restaurant?
It was nothing.
You're seeing things
more often now. aren't you?
No.
Do you remember what we practiced?
I can handle it.
You can't. Judy. you can't.
You need to shut it out.
Trust me. after a lifetime of this.
I promise you.
you don't want it.
I got it.
I love you.
I love you too. Mom.
Should we go rescue Tony from your father?
Please.
Thanks for the encouragement.
There's a nice bounce!
Come on. Drew. you got this.
Get him. Get him.
Oh!
Tony! You're up.
Sure.
- All good?
- Yeah.
Good luck. buddy.
-  All right.
- Jacket off!
- The jacket. I got it.
- Okay!
-  Ready?
- Yeah.
You need to hop around a little more?
- No. I'm good. sir. I'm good.
- All right. Here we go. Ready?
♪ Let's play ♪
Whoa!
-  One more.
-  All right.
♪ Let's sway ♪
♪ Under the moonlight
The serious moonlight ♪
Oh!
Twenty-one. eighteen!
Good game.
Tough luck. Tony.
Almost thought you had a chance.
- Congratulations.
- Oh. man.
-  That was so good.
- Nice job.
- We got a winner.
- Why did I hit it?
Sorry.
You okay?
Yeah.
Still undefeated.
I'm gonna get another drink.
Oh. I'll come. Uh.
Mom. Dad. you want something?
- No. thank you. sweetheart.
- You good?
Yeah. I'm good. I'm good.
We have beers?
- Yeah.
-  Whoo.
Don't think I didn't notice.
- It's spick and span.
- I'm trying.
-  Yeah.
-  This is. uh...
Sorry to interrupt. Um...
Actually. I. um... You know.
I was hoping to say something?
Sure. What's on your mind?
Yeah. well. um...
You know. it's good that Judy's gone.
'cause what I wanted to say was. um...
I'm just gonna...
Uh...
So...
I bought this a week after I met her.
Soon. I know. and I know
we've only been dating for six months.
but...
You know. when you know. you know.
And I-I just--
I can't imagine my life without her.
So...
what I'm trying to say is.
I-I... I would love to have your blessing.
It's beautiful. Tony.
You do know...
...that our family
is not like other families?
And Judy. um...
...she's our little girl.
And. um. you know. you're right.
it has been a very short time.
But we barely knew each other
when we got engaged.
- Well--
- Ed was shipping out.
But I think that... I don't know.
I think that we just knew.
Mm-hmm.
Of course. you have our blessing.
Mr. Warren?
Yeah. um...
Tony. um... You're a good kid...
Ed...
And... Well. they've only known
each other six months.
Don't be silly.
But she just said that you guys--
- Yeah. well. that...
- Yeah...
...was a-a different time.
Okay. um...
Maybe this was too early?
- Yeah. there we go.
- No.
So. I will come back in a month and--
A month?
Ed...
What is that?
- Sh...
- Oh.
Is that for me?
Yes.
- Judy. I was asking--
- Yes!
Yes! Obviously. yes!
Yes!
It's beautiful.
Is this why
you were so nervous in the car?
Sure was.
- Did you see it?
- I did! I did.
It's so pretty.
- Oh. honey.
- Thank you. sir.
- Thank you.
- Congratulations.
So pretty.
- You happy?
- Yeah.
- Congrats. Tony.
- Thanks. man.
You know. Tony. he seems like a good egg.
Yeah. yeah...
Judy's got good instincts.
You just. have to let her go.
let her walk her own path.
Yeah.
Oh. uh. by the way...
we've had a couple calls.
Some families reaching out.
They could use your...
special assistance.
So. what are we talking about?
Are they local. or--
Ed.
Yeah.
We're sorry. Father.
Those days are behind us now.
I know. I guess I just--
I just had to try.
- For old times' sake.
- Sure.
- Happy birthday.
- Thank you.
You look good for an old guy.
We're just gonna pretend.
like nothing's going on?
Father Jensen has submitted
our case to the archdiocese.
And so what?
You're just gonna let us
live in a haunted house?
Don't talk to your father like that!
It's all right. I got this. Mom.
Just. please. stop fighting!
Oh. honey...
It's okay. honey.
Please. Dad. can't we got to a motel?
There's eight of us. sweetie.
We can't afford that.
As I was saying. Father Jensen has said--
"Father Jensen says."
- God. I've heard that before.
- The church has a process.
They work with people
who come and document...
these things.
"These things?"
To prove it's all real!
"To prove it's all real?"
It's real!
- It wants to kill us!
- No. no.
No. it does!
You-- You don't believe us. do you?
- No. no. Dawn.
- Do you?
- that is not what I am saying.
- No. you don't believe us.
- That is not what I'm saying!
- You don't believe us.
just 'cause it hasn't happened to you.
It's happening to all of us!
Not the same way it's happened to me. Dad!
I cannot live like this anymore.
None of us can!
Either you don't believe us.
or you can't do anything about it.
Which is it?
- Jesus fucking Christ...
- Dawn...
- Hey!
- No. no.
- I'm not gonna wait. Don't.
- Just leave it. No. no. Hon...
Oh. no. Dawn. Come...
...got you that nice brooch?
-  Yeah.
-  Oh... yeah.
-  Go on. open it.
- Okay.
-  Go on!
- I'm excited to see what it is.
Oh. the tension!
Oh. my God!
It's kinda weird.
Thanks. Grandpa.
You're welcome. honey.
Thanks. Grandma.
...cake!
Are you excited
for your cake. Heather?
Simon wants some cake. too.
-  Here we go!
- Yeah!
Ready?
Hey. she blew out my candle.
-  Who?
-  Dawn!
-  Oh.
-  I did not!
You did.
Here we go!
Ready?
Hey. she blew--
What was that?
Simon wants some cake. too.
-  Here we go!
-  Yeah!
Ready?
-  Here we go!
-  Yeah!
Ready?
-  Here we go!
-  Yeah!
Ready?
Hey. she blew out my candle.
Simon wants some cake. too.
-  Here we go!
-  Yeah!
Ready?
Dad.
Jack! Jack!
Jack. Jack. Jack.
The girls!
God!
Oh. my God. Heather.
Baby. what happened? What happened?
Someone's here! Someone's here!
No one's here. honey. No one's here!
-  He's in here!
-  Heather! Poor. baby.
We can't live like this. Jack!
We need to do something!
Oh. poor Heather!
The devil has come to Pennsylvania.
In the coal mining hills of West Pittston.
this family is under siege
by the supernatural.
This is my parents and. um...
We had quite a bit of disturbance
- in through the kitchen there...
- Jack and Janet Smurl...
- ...from the ceiling.
- ...claim that an evil presence
has found its way into their home.
Curiosity seekers.
those that believe.
and those that do not. lined Chase Street.
Wednesday. to see the haunted house.
We're live in three. two...
Welcome to Larry King Live!
Good evening.
on this Monday night.
Cast out. ye evil demons!
Our guests. to begin things.
are Janet and Jack Smurl.
Do you guess. haunted by what?
We didn't guess by anything. Larry.
See. we weren't thinking
in terms of supernatural.
I mean. nobody does.
Jack Smurl says that a demon
assaulted him in the middle of the night.
- paralyzing his body.
- It woke my wife.
and then there was screaming.
Is this really a haunting.
or is this some elaborate hoax?
Eight people live in this house.
eight people have experienced this.
Eight people are not crazy.
We're asking... for help.
- Someone. anyone. help us.
- Maureen.
Oh. my gosh!
- It's little Judy Warren!
- Hey. Brenda.
You brought your mom. too.
- Our local celebrity.
- Thank you.
Oh. Brenda... How's your family?
Oh. good. good. good.
You know. maybe when we're done.
you can tell me my future?
I'm kidding. I know that's not your thing!
You've got your investigations and all.
- Well. not anymore.
-  Okay. So. Mrs. Warren.
Maureen'll get you a coffee or something.
And sweetie. I'll take you back.
We'll try on that beautiful dress!
Wish I could meet a guy like Tony.
- What about Dom?
- Ugh.
We broke up. Again.
I'm sorry. There's plenty
more fish in the sea.
You're very sweet.
You were too pretty for him. anyway.
Stop!
- Ow!
- Oh. I'm so sorry!
Looks like I nicked you there.
Yeah.
Maureen?
You gonna get that?
That girl's an idiot. I'll be right back.
I was starting to get
really claustrophobic.
Brenda?
You okay down there. Brenda?
Ow.
Brenda?
♪ Lucy Locket lost her pocket
Kitty Fisher found it ♪
♪ Not a penny was there in it
Only ribbon 'round it ♪
Mom!
♪ Lucy Locket lost her pocket
Kitty Fisher found it ♪
♪ Not a penny there was in it
Only ribbon 'round it ♪
♪ You're not there! ♪
Judy!
What's wrong? Hey.
What happened?
It's okay.
Mr. Smurl. Mr. Smurl.
-  Careful.
- Jack.
Can you back off. please?
What's going on in your house?
- Please. can you make some room?
- Back off!
Please. have some respect!
- Out of respect for my mother.
- Please. back off!
-  Give us space. please!
-  Is she okay?
For heaven's sake.
outta my face!
Careful.
-  Go away!
-  You'll be okay. Mom.
Kids. Grandma's gonna be fine.
don't worry.
Dawn. look after your mother.
Can you get out of my--
- Jack. I'll see you there. okay?
- See you at the hospital.
I'm gonna go with Ma.
- We'll be in touch. sweetie.
-  Yeah.
Why won't it stop?
Mom. look.
Yes.
- That's Simon.
- Oh. hey. Simon.
I grew up with a dog like this.
- Oh. you did?
- Yeah.
Th-- That ambulance out there...
...who was that?
It's my mother-in-law.
Some...
Something pushed her down the stairs.
It's getting worse.
And we can't afford to leave.
I'm so glad that you're here.
We really thought that
the church had forgotten about us.
Mrs. Smurl. uh...
The church doesn't know I'm here.
I'm actually from Connecticut.
But I have worked
with cases similar to yours.
and I have been following your story
very closely on the news.
I thought I might be able to help.
In the name of the Father.
the Son. and the Holy Spirit.
What happened down there?
Something's here.
You're leaving?
We are gonna help you.
The church will listen to me.
I promise you. they'll listen.
Can I help you?
Bishop McKenna. please.
Of course. And you are?
Father Gordon.
One minute.
I have a Father Gordon.
- This is regarding?
- The Smurls.
They're a family from West Pittston.
It's urgent.
He's here about a family
from West Pittston.
He says it's urgent.
All right.
He'll just be one moment.
Father? Are you all right?
Yes. I'm...
I'm sorry.
Hel-- Hello?
Father Gordon?
- Judy?
-  You can go now.
I am protected by God Almighty.
maker of heaven and Earth.
of all that is seen and unseen.
My faith is my armor.
God's light...
God protect me!
There she is!
See. you've always gotta check
if she's got a spark.
Ah.
Kept thinking it was the carburetor.
Should have checked the spark plug.
Nice work.
Well. you know. I. uh.
I couldn't afford a mechanic in college.
so I had to teach myself.
Hey. how much has Judy told you
about what we do?
Enough to not ask many questions.
Come inside. I wanna show you something.
Don't touch anything.
Everything you see in here
is either haunted. cursed.
or been used in some
sort of ritualistic practice.
Nothing's a toy.
Not even the toys.
If all these things are so evil.
why do you keep them around?
Why not just destroy them?
It's complicated.
Sometimes that makes things worse.
Sometimes... they just won't let you.
We've found it safer
to keep the genie in the bottle.
It's better in here than out there.
How many cases you guys had?
Cases? Oh.
Maybe a thousand?
A thousand?
Yeah. well. We started young.
about your age.
Mmm. It's funny. This room.
every little thing in it...
...is our story.
It's our life's work.
Listen. the other day?
I get it.
Yeah I-- I was just... nervous.
and you're kinda intimidating.
We almost lost Judy.
She was stillborn.
For probably a minute.
It was the longest minute of our lives.
And as a parent.
that's something you never forget.
So. while I know she's your fiancée.
for us.
she will always be that little baby.
fighting for her life.
I understand. sir.
Do you?
What's wrong?
What?
Father Gordon. he was a good man.
A man of God.
And he helped so many people.
I didn't know Father
to be a man of despair.
No. Father Gordon was light.
And he brought that light
to me and my family.
when we needed him most.
I only wish that...
...we could've done the same for him.
Mr. Warren? Mrs. Warren?
Yes?
I'm sorry. we never met.
My name is Father Ziegler.
You're actually both a bit infamous
within certain circles of the church.
Yes. we're aware.
But Gordon always spoke highly of you.
He believed in the mission.
And the things you did together.
He considered you both friends.
Thank you. Father.
Excuse me. Father.
Yes?
Mm.
Where was it?
Where did he die?
Pennsylvania.
God only knows why he was out there.
What?
♪ Lucy Locket lost her pocket ♪
♪ Kitty Fisher found it ♪
Lorraine. What? What's wrong?
It's Judy.
There's something wrong with Judy.
Where is she?
Oh. boy.
Ma'am.
can I ask you a few questions?
Hey. stay back from here. okay?
Whatever is going on in that house.
we are getting Judy.
and we are taking her home.
All right. Excuse us.
Sorry. Excuse us.
It's Ed and Lorraine Warren.
Mrs. Warren. what are you doing here?
Mrs. Warren. have you been called in
for reinforcements?
What's in the house?
Mr. Warren. will you
be performing an exorcism today?
Excuse me.
Are the Smurls hiding something?
- Do you know the Smurls?
-  Ed and Lorraine!
Are you coming out
of retirement?
Sir?
- Sir. can you tell us your name?
-  Hey. just back off.
What's your connection
to the Warrens. sir?
Ed and Lorraine...
You okay?
Mr. Smurl?
Ed Warren.
Uh. yeah. This is my wife.
Lorraine. Yes. yes!
Please. come in. Please.
Oh. thank you so much for coming.
We hear you're the experts.
People told us you were retired.
Well.
I'm so sorry.
We're looking for our daughter.
Mom?
Judy!
That is Janet a-and Jack Smurl.
Thank God you're safe.
What are you doing out here?
This is not like you.
Father Gordon was here.
He came here just before he died.
I put two and two together.
and I found them.
- It's been going on for months.
- We need to go.
What? No. Mom. Mom.
I'm so sorry. Ed. we need to go.
- You're leaving?
- Yes. we're leaving.
Wait. what?
Really sorry if we've intruded.
- We can't leave!
- We can't stay.
- We can talk about this outside.
- Mom!
It's been a long drive.
Again. we're really sorry. Come on. Judy.
-  Say something.
- Stop!
We don't run from fights. right?
I mean. that's what
you'd always tell each other.
when there was a family
that needed you.
As a kid. I didn't understand
why you had to leave.
Why you gave so much of yourselves
to people you didn't know.
And even now. I don't know.
I don't know why I'm here. I really don't.
But we're all here now.
And they need us.
They need you.
Any comments for us?
Mr. Warren. do
you think it's a real haunting?
We should have never gone to the press.
Now our neighbors can't stand us.
They think we wanted this.
I didn't know
it was gonna turn into a circus.
We wanted someone like you. experts.
People who've dealt with this before.
L-Let's... take this back
to the beginning. When did it start?
- Uh. Heather's confirmation.
- Yeah.
What do you mean. you saw him die?
I mean. were you here?
No. back home. In a vision.
But... it was different.
Did you tell your mom?
No. I can't talk to her anymore.
She's always so...
- Worried.
- Yeah.
There's something else.
I don't know how to say it.
but it's like...
...something wants me to be here.
So your parents were living here?
Which one of you? Which parents?
Yeah. they've been with us all along.
since we moved in. and um...
He started making pancakes.
So. is this. like. a normal case?
They're never normal.
No. I mean. do you always cook pancakes?
Is that part of the process?
Sometimes it's waffles.
No. every case is different.
Every family's different.
One thing that's always the same
is the fear.
You can see it in their eyes.
And a demon will prey on that.
It'll try to isolate them.
use their fears against them.
So part of the job is just...
letting them know they're not alone.
Right.
Judy told me you were a cop.
What happened? Why'd you quit?
It's nothing.
Okay. so...
I was working in Bloomfield.
You know. small town.
Nothing ever happens.
Me and my partner.
we get a domestic violence call.
And we pull up to the house.
and we hear fighting inside.
So. I knock on the door.
And immediately.
the door flies open.
and this guy shoves
a twelve-gauge shotgun right in my face.
And I hear... click.
I. uh...
I unfreeze.
and. uh. we take the guy down.
Arrest him.
Later. my partner comes up to me.
and he says. "You're a dead man."
He shows me the shotgun.
It was loaded.
Primer was struck on the shell.
Misfire.
I figure. there's a world where I'm dead.
Where I never grow old.
I never have kids.
I never get to marry your daughter.
So next day. I-I quit.
and I go out and buy that ring for Judy.
- This is my wastepaper basket. Bert.
- Of course. it's your waste basket!
- Oh. yeah.
- You put it on my head!
- Thank you. Bert.
- "Thank you?"
That's my wastepaper basket
for throwing stuff in
when I make a mistake.
Terrific. Okay. now. Ernie. Ernie...
Should we do a silly face? Yeah?
Sorry. the flash was supposed to be off.
I just thought I could...
...document it all.
Everything okay?
Yeah.
I just realized.
I've never seen you guys at work.
I feel it. too.
Stay here.
- Mom. I can help.
- Judy. you promised.
Mommy. Mommy!
Mommy--
Hey. Carin.
Sorry.
It's okay.
Uh. what's her name?
This is Susie.
Hey. Susie.
Do you like dolls?
Uh...
Not really.
Get away from her!
I know what you did.
You dirty girl!
You filthy girl!
No!
The spirits. there are three of them.
They never lived in this house.
but on this land.
This was farmland.
Uh...
There was a woman.
She was wild. She...
Just so tormented.
She had an affair. and...
...her husband went insane.
He took an axe. and he went after her.
She hid in the basement.
but she wasn't alone.
She went with her elderly mother.
- And he killed them both.
- Look. we've seen
violent manifestations like that before.
So why is this different?
The three spirits are a façade.
Something else is blocking my vision.
Hiding behind them.
Demonic?
It's controlling the spirits.
It's using them against the Smurls.
But what's it want?
I mean. this has been going on for months.
What's it waiting for?
Judy!
Mom?
Can you come up here. please?
Oh.
Annabelle?
Judy?
Are you there?
Carin?
-  Judy!
Your head!
What happened?
There's something in the attic.
It can't be.
It... found us.
Lorraine?
No. Lorraine. No. don't.
Ed. something's changed.
Something's different.
Then. after about a week.
Judy recovered.
The doctors said
they'd never seen anything like it.
She was a miracle.
But as for that mirror.
we never saw it again...
...until today.
But I don't understand.
Heather and I threw that thing away.
With these things.
it's never that simple.
It wasn't done with you.
and it wasn't done with us.
Okay. so then what happened to the woman
from the antique store?
We don't know.
Uh...
We never went back.
That thing in your attic is a demon.
It's the first one
that we ever encountered.
We were young. and we were scared.
and we almost lost our daughter.
So. we told ourselves that
the risk was just too great.
so we couldn't chance going back.
So. yes.
We ran away.
I'll...
...take it as a good sign
you're still here.
Mm.
We're not leaving you.
Some water?
Sorry.
So. what now?
How do you get rid of it?
Ed! You're really
gonna take that thing home?
We can't leave it here.
Artifact room is the only place
that can contain it.
All right. West Pittston.
back home to Monroe. Take 80.
Lorraine and Judy can stay behind.
Wait. 84 is faster.
Eighty is much quicker this time of night.
Listen to me. whatever happens tonight.
you have got to do what I say. okay?
Got it.
What? What is it?
It's nothin'.
Everything okay?
I-It's just something Lorraine said.
Something feels different.
Mom. I'm-- I'm sorry.
No. I'm sorry.
I should have never let you stay.
Once we start. there's no going back.
Don't look at it.
And don't touch it directly.
Just keep your gloves on.
Anything can happen.
And most likely. anything will.
"St. Michael the Archangel.
defend us in the day of battle.
Be our safeguard against the wickedness
and snares of the devil."
"May God rebuke him.
And by the power of God.
cast into hell. Satan.
and all other evil spirits
who prowl through the world.
seeking the ruin of souls."
"Amen."
- I'll get the car ready.
- Yeah.
We'll be down in a second.
All right.
-  You ready?
- Yeah.
Two. three... Yeah.
-  Come on. Simon!
-  Let's go. Simon!
Come on. Simon!
- Come on! Be a good boy.
- Come on!
Girls. get him outta here.
We're trying!
So. is it just drywall
underneath the insulation?
Yeah.
So. if we step off these boards.
- we're going--
- Straight through the ceiling.
Don't wanna make it too easy.
Is it just me or...
or does it feel like it's getting heavier?
It is.
Sometimes these things can be...
...stubborn.
Oh!
You okay?
- Yeah. I'm good.
- Okay.
Ed...
Look.
Keep moving.
Come on!
Judy... Judy. what's wrong?
Mom.
I don't feel good.
We're almost there.
Don't look at it!
Don't-- don't look at it!
She's with us!
Jack. it's just us.
She's here! I saw her. Ed.
- I saw her.
- No. it's just us.
- She is here.
- Jack.
- Focus on what you're doing.
- I saw her. She's here.
Jack. watch where you're going.
Oh!
Jack. get outta the way! No!
Daddy!
Stay right here.
Mommy!
Ed? What's going on?
Jack! What happened?
Get back!
No. get back!
Just keep everybody away.
- Let me go get Tony.
- No. I can do this.
Just help me up.
Lorraine. stay down there!
Keep everybody down there.
Come on. Come on.
Yes!
What the--
Oh. man. Oh. God.
My God.
What?
No.
♪ Lucy Locket ♪
♪ Lost her pocket ♪
♪ Kitty Fisher found it ♪
♪ Not a penny was there in it ♪
♪ Only ribbon 'round it ♪
Mommy?
I don't feel so good.
Judy?
We've been waiting so patiently
for little Judy to come back to us.
-  It's okay.
-  I'm sorry. Ed.
Okay. It's okay.
Easy. easy. easy.
Simon. get back.
Judy?
Simon. come back.
What's going on?
Girls. come.
Pull him. Heather!
Mommy?
No! No!
-  Mommy!
- Hey!
- It's okay.
-  Simon!
- Oh. no!
-  Let me in!
-  Stop! No!
-  No!
-  Simon!
- No! You get away from them!
You get away from them!
Judy.
No. No!
No. Judy. look at me.
Look in my eyes.
Daddy?
Yeah.
Come on. come on.
It's-- Judy--
- Open the door! Open the door!
- Open the door!
- It won't open!
-  ♪ Lucy Locket... ♪
- Judy. listen to my voice.
- I know you're in there. It's Daddy!
- ♪ ...Lost her pocket ♪
♪ Kitty Fisher found it ♪
I know you can hear me. Judy. Judy!
♪ You're not there ♪
Judy.
♪ Lucy Locket... ♪
Mommy!
No!
Wait there!
I'm going 'round the back. okay?
Oh. God.
Lorraine?
Hey. you okay?
Tony.
- Stay here! Stay here!
- No!
No. no. Mommy. don't leave us!
Are you okay?
What should I do?
Should I call the police? An ambulance?
- There's no time.
- Mommy!
Get Jack and the girls.
and get outta here.
Jack?
She's going up to the attic.
Go!
Come on. quickly. girls! Get out!
-  Let me help you!
-  It's okay. It's okay.
Ed!
It wanted Judy.
It's always been Judy.
Get the book!
It's all right.
Judy!
No! Judy!
Ed! The knife! Ed.
Oh...
No!
Ed!
Get her down!
-  Tony! Lift her up!
- Get her down! Get her down!
- Oh. my God! Judy! Judy!
-  Oh. God!
Oh. my God! Judy!
Come on!
Judy!
Hang on. Okay. Okay.
- She's not got a pulse.
-  No.
Get outta the way.
Just get outta the way!
- Ed. I can help!
- I got it!
- I've got it!
- Judy...
- Oh. God! No!
- Come on. baby. Come on. baby. please.
- Come on. Judy.
- Please. please.
- No! Oh. my baby! My baby!
- Come on. honey.
Come on. baby.
- You can do this.
- Please. Lord!
Please. don't take her. Please. God.
Please.
No...
- Ed?
- I can't-- Keep going.
Okay.
Oh. Father!
One. two.
Come on!
Come on.
Oh. God!
Thank you! Thank you. God. Thank you.
Judy.
Mom?
Dad?
Ed.
Stop it!
In the name of the Father.
the Son. and the Holy Spirit.
In nomine Patris. et Filii.
et Spiritus Sancti.
We cast you out. Every unclean spirit!
Every satanic power!
Every legion!
And by the power of our Lord Jesus Christ!
Ed!
Omnem potentiam satanicam!
Incursionem adversarii infernalis!
♪ Lucy Locket... ♪
Omnem legionem et sectam diabolicam!
In nomine et virtute!
Shut your mouth!
No!
- Ed!
- You're gonna watch him die.
I command you with the word of God!
You're not there.
You're not there. You're not there.
They won't go away.
- ♪ Lucy Locket lost her pocket ♪
- ♪ Kitty Fisher found it ♪
- ♪ Not a penny was there in it ♪
- ♪ Only ribbon 'round it ♪
You can shut it out. Just shut it out.
Get her outta here!
No.
Don't look away.
Don't shut it out.
Mom.
Don't run!
You're...
not...
...there.
Bye. Judy.
-  Good?
- Good.
All right.
Hey.
Welcome to the family.
So beautiful.
You may kiss the bride.
♪ I wanna comfort you ♪
♪ Just let your tears... ♪
I had a vision last night.
Yeah?
- Mm.
- What was it?
Our future.
♪ Like when you were a child ♪
♪ I'll do what I can do ♪
I dreamed
that we became grandparents.
Oh.
And that baby's
definitely gonna get spoiled.
We finally got around
to writing our book...
...and it was terrible.
But it shared
the story of our family...
and all those
that we met along the way.
And we still passed on
what we learned to a new generation.
And we never stopped having adventures.
And we never stopped
helping people...
...even when the only thing we could do
was talk to them on the phone.
And then we were old.
And Judy and Tony
were visiting us with their kids.
And they brought their kids.
And I felt warmth...
and love...
...and comfort for all of my days.
That sounds...
...just about right.
♪ I'll put the weight on you ♪
♪ And I'll do the same thing
That you do ♪
♪ I'll put the weight on you ♪
...are nationally
renowned demon chasers.
...ghost hunters
Ed and Lorraine Warren.
We're in the home of Janet and Jack Smurl.
...family
has experienced the rappings.
all the way down the hallway.
There are spirits that can do
great physical harm to people.
In the name of Jesus Christ
and all that's holy.
we command you to leave right now.
He felt like
he was being strangled.
You would see the child pull
invisible hands away from his throat.
When a person
becomes frightened.
they throw off psychic energy
into the atmosphere.
which an evil spirit can use
as fuel to manifest even more phenomena.
When you challenge the demonic.
it waits until you are
the most vulnerable.
then it strikes.
Diabolical spirit can appear
to anyone in any guise it wishes.
...name of Jesus Christ.
I command you to reveal your identity.
The front door would open. slam.
and this voice would say. "Janet?"
And. yeah. this how
they would swing. back and forth.
when the infestation was occurring.
I don't care if you wanna
call it a devil or a ghost or a demon.
something in this home
has the intelligence to inflict
physical and psychological harm
upon this family.